<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<personnel>
    <person color="red" tier="1">
        <name>Fleet Control</name>
        <effect>You may have one more ship than your fleet supply would normally allow in systems containing a friendly space dock.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="1">
        <name>Moneylender</name>
        <effect>After building ships, you may exhaust any number of space docks to receive their planets' resource values in destroyers in those systems. When refreshing a space dock, exhaust its planet.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="2">
        <name>Marauder</name>
        <effect>If your mercenary is not on the board, place it in any friendly system, if able. If your mercenary is on the board, you may move it to any friendly system.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="2">
        <name>Cultist</name>
        <effect>When you have three or more ships of the same type in a system, they each receive +1 on all normal combat rolls. This bonus is lost for the rest of the battle when one of them is taken as a casualty.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="3">
        <name>Usurper</name>
        <effect>Receive two bonus votes for each of your capital ships in or adjacent to Mecatol Rex, up to a maximum of six.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="3">
        <name>Advisor</name>
        <effect>At the beginning of each action phase, receive one bonus command counter in your command pool. The first time you activate a system each round, you may place a second command counter from your command pool. Each of your ships in that system receives +1 during the first round of space combat.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="red" tier="4">
        <name>Conqueror</name>
        <effect>Choose a type of ship. Whenever you destroy a ship of that type, set it aside. Return them after the development phase.</effect>
    </person>
    
    <person color="blue" tier="1">
        <name>Astronomer</name>
        <effect>Your carriers may collect deep space tokens. Upon collecting your third, receive one blue technology at no cost, ignoring all of its prerequisites.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="1">
        <name>Lookout</name>
        <effect>At the end of each battle phase, do this twice: you may move one destroyer or cruiser into an adjacent empty system.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="2">
        <name>Cartographer</name>
        <effect>Your ships may travel to and from the wormhole nexus.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="2">
        <name>Scavenger</name>
        <effect>Each time one of your fleets moves through an asteroid field, it receives two fighters.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="3">
        <name>Admiral</name>
        <effect>Each of your ships receives +1 movement when traveling towards neutral systems.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="3">
        <name>Technician</name>
        <effect>You may place an alpha or beta wormhole token on one of your space docks. Only you may use this wormhole.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="blue" tier="4">
        <name>Champion</name>
        <effect>During each round of a space battle, your ships receive a combat bonus equal to the difference between the number of your ships and the number of your opponent's non-fighter ships (zero if not outnumbered).</effect>
    </person>
    
    <person color="green" tier="1">
        <name>Envoy</name>
        <effect>When voting, you may cast two free votes for each resolution as long as they follow the speaker’s intent.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="1">
        <name>Salvager</name>
        <effect>When scuttling non-fighter ships, receive one bonus resource each the next time you build units.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="2">
        <name>Engineer</name>
        <effect>Your space docks have a minimum production capacity of four (before technology and racial abilities).</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="2">
        <name>Mechanic</name>
        <effect>Each of your SASs roll two dice each combat round.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="3">
        <name>Chancellor</name>
        <effect>Each round, the first time a system containing one of your ships is activated by another player, he must place a second command counter from his command pool, if able.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="3">
        <name>Explorer</name>
        <effect>Each of your carriers rolls normal combat dice at 6+.</effect>
    </person>
    <person color="green" tier="4">
        <name>Tactician</name>
        <effect>During each round of a space battle, each of your ships receives +1 on combat rolls if there is no opposing ship of the same type.</effect>
    </person>
</personnel>
