<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<technology>
    <tech color="red">
        <name>Hylar V Assault Laser</name>
        <effect>Each of your cruisers and destroyers receives +1 on all combat rolls.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Hylar V Assault Laser">
        <name>Ion Cannons</name>
        <effect>Each of your dreadnoughts receives +2 on all combat rolls.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Hylar V Assault Laser">
        <name>ADT</name>
        <effect>Each of your destroyers receives +1 on anti-fighter barrage rolls. Opposing fighters must take a minimum number of casualties equal to the number of friendly destroyers present during anti-fighter barrage.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Hylar V Assault Laser" prereqOR="Cybernetics">
        <name>Hyper Metabolism</name>
        <effect>At the end of each combat round, each of your destroyers receive +1 on all combat rolls for the remainder of the battle.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Ion Cannons" prereqAND="Enviro Compensator">
        <name>Magen Defence Grid</name>
        <effect>You may not build spaceborne artillery systems. Your dreadnoughts have a spaceborne artillery system capacity of one.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Magen Defence Grid">
        <name>Auxiliary Drones</name>
        <effect>Your fleets that contain at least one dreadnought roll an additional combat die at 9+. This die benefits from all modifiers to dreadnought combat dice.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Magen Defence Grid" prereqAND="Cybernetics">
        <name>Assault Cannon</name>
        <effect>If you have three or fewer ships present, each of your cruisers may roll one pre-combat die at +3.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="red" prereq="Ion Cannons" prereqAND="Fighter Bays">
        <name>Deep Space Cannon</name>
        <effect>As an action, you may activate a system adjacent to one of your fleets to begin a siege. If your siege token is in that system, destroy one capital ship of the defender's choice, then inflict one hit for each adjacent system containing at least one of your dreadnoughts. Otherwise, place your siege token in that system. </effect>
    </tech>
    
    <tech color="blue">
        <name>Antimass Deflectors</name>
        <effect>Your ships may move through asteroid field and ion storm systems. Your ships suffer no movement penalty when leaving nebulae.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="Antimass Deflectors">
        <name>Striker Fleets</name>
        <effect>Your destroyers and cruisers receive a combat bonus equal to their remaining movement points when attacking in a small battle.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="Antimass Deflectors">
        <name>XRD Transporters</name>
        <effect>Your carriers and dreadnoughts receive +1 movement.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="XRD Transporters" prereqAND="Hylar V Assault Laser">
        <name>Fighter Bays</name>
        <effect>Your dreadnoughts now have a fighter capacity of three.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="XRD Transporters" prereqAND="Neural Computing">
        <name>Type IV Drive</name>
        <effect>Your cruisers and flagships now receive +1 movement.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="Type IV Drive">
        <name>Advanced Fighters</name>
        <effect>Your fighters may now move independently with a movement rate of two and receive +1 on all combat rolls.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="Arkan Iridium" prereqOR="Integrated Economy">
        <name>Fleet Logistics</name>
        <effect>Once per round, you may flip one of your command counters on the board.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="blue" prereq="Striker Fleets" prereqAND="Magen Defence Grid">
        <name>Wave Deflectors</name>
        <effect>Your ships may pass through systems containing enemy fleets.</effect>
    </tech>
    
    <tech color="green" prereq="Enviro Compensator" prereqOR="Antimass Deflectors">
        <name>Stasis Capsules</name>
        <effect>Your cruisers and dreadnoughts may now carry one ground force unit each.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Stasis Capsules" prereqAND="Enviro Compensator">
        <name>Hydroponics</name>
        <effect>In all systems that do not contain any of your capital ships, you may have one more ship present than your fleet supply would normally allow.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Stasis Capsules" prereqOR="Antimass Deflectors">
        <name>Cybernetics</name>
        <effect>Each of your fighters receives +1 on all combat rolls.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Cybernetics">
        <name>Biomechanical Circuits</name>
        <effect>At the beginning of each action phase, receive one additional command counter in your command pool.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Cybernetics">
        <name>Xeno Psychology</name>
        <effect>Each round, all of your ships receive +1 on all combat rolls during the first combat round during the first battle with each player.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Xeno Psychology">
        <name>Neural Computing</name>
        <effect>You may research up to four technologies per round (regardless of the number of space docks you have) at a base cost of six each.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Hydroponics" prereqOR="Xeno Psychology">
        <name>Biosphere Influence</name>
        <effect>Each of your planets without a space dock has a production capacity equal to its resource value and a fighter capacity equal to its influence value.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="green" prereq="Assault Cannon">
        <name>Organ Printing</name>
        <effect>Each of your dreadnoughts has a production capacity of one. At the beginning of the devel- opment phase, you may exhaust one of your space docks to give one of your dreadnoughts its production capacity.</effect>
    </tech>
    
    <tech color="yellow">
        <name>Enviro Compensator</name>
        <effect>The production capacity of your space docks is increased by one.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Enviro Compensator">
        <name>Transfabrication</name>
        <effect>Upon losing a dreadnought, immediately replace it with a destroyer. At the end of combat, if at least one such destroyer remains, you may replace one of them with a damaged dreadnought.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Enviro Compensator">
        <name>Sarween Tools</name>
        <effect>Whenever you produce units at any space dock, you now receive one additional resource with which to build units.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Transfabrication" prereqAND="ADT">
        <name>Duranium Armor</name>
        <effect>After taking casualties, you may repair one damaged ship.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Sarween Tools" prereqAND="Ion Cannons">
        <name>War Sun</name>
        <effect>You may now produce war suns. War suns receive one bonus movement if they do not end their turn in a system containing enemy ships.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Cybernetics" prereqAND="Sarween Tools">
        <name>Arkan Iridium</name>
        <effect>The cost of your space docks is reduced to two. You may build space docks at any time during the development phase.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Sarween Tools" prereqAND="XRD Transporters">
        <name>Space Gates</name>
        <effect>Each of your space docks is considered adjacent to each other. When moving from or through your space docks to a neutral system, each of your ships receives +1 movement.</effect>
    </tech>
    <tech color="yellow" prereq="Ion Cannons" prereqAND="Cybernetics">
        <name>Integrated Economy</name>
        <effect>When building ships at a space dock, you may place the newly constructed units in any neutral system adjacent to one of your space docks.</effect>
    </tech>

</technology>
